<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>K E N O </title>
	<subtitle>Media artist.</subtitle>
	<link href="https://kenokeno.bingo/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://kenokeno.bingo/"/>
	<updated>2019-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://kenokeno.bingo/</id>
	<author>
		<name>K E N O </name>
		<email>win@kenokeno.bingo</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>I am a Machine</title>
		<link href="https://kenokeno.bingo/works/i-am-a-machine/"/>
		<updated>2016-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://kenokeno.bingo/works/i-am-a-machine/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kenokeno.bingo/img/iamamachine.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Marilyn&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://marilyn.kenokeno.bingo/&quot;&gt;How to modernise Andy Warhol?&lt;/a&gt; The postmodern Warhol is a machine, it is processing Marilyn with a computer. Thereby Marilyn gets different functions, aesthetics and charisma.
A file is destroyed on a low level in order to get an aesthetic output on the higher level. Generally, Warhol used the same principle. He used modern originals, adopting and arranging them in his special way of expression. Although he tried to imitate a machine, he made obviously mistake. In fact, this is what makes his works especially interesting. Maybe this is the main topic of Warhol’s works: mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Martha Stuart</title>
		<link href="https://kenokeno.bingo/works/martha-stuart/"/>
		<updated>2016-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://kenokeno.bingo/works/martha-stuart/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;padding:56.25% 0 0 0;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/195532176?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do people feel about talking to machines? As always, people have mixed feelings about dialogues with a machine. On the one hand people like to talk to Siri instead of typing long texts, on the other hand we are still not comfortable with close relationships between machines and humans. If a relationship is defined by two entities having an emotional bonding to each other, there even is no such thing as a relationship between humans and machines. A machine cannot feel – a machine can only think in an algorithmic and computable way. Maybe this is the reason why communication with machines is that ambivalent.
Since humans are able to think emotionally and self-consciously, people ask for the meaning of life. And because we have not been able to answer this question for thousands of years, we like to ask other entities. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hitchhiker%27s_Guide_to_the_Galaxy&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Douglas Adams there are two computers being asked this question: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aboZctrHfK8&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deep Thought&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and planet Earth. &lt;em&gt;Deep Thought&lt;/em&gt;’s answer was “42,” but the question was needed. So the Earth was built – it was destroyed, before the simulation was finished, though. So it is time for a new machine. A machine which is corrupted and weird, which does not even try to answer this question properly. Martha Stuart is a performance for one human and one machine. The human asks, the machine answers. There is no need for a universal meaning of life because there is none – nevertheless, people always strive for it. This new machine convinces them nonsense is the only answer that can be given. Advertising and capitalism wants us to belive that buying is the mechanism that keeps the earth spinning. So the machine answers with commercials. This machine is not supposed to enlighten the human and the audience, it is supposed to confuse and intrude their minds. It wants to sell, but to be weird and funny at the same time. It has also no unique voice, but this mix of different speakers: A machines does not have a character, since it has no emotions. There is some output, some data, but no personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/playlists/240688462&amp;color=%23000000&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>GOODTHINK</title>
		<link href="https://kenokeno.bingo/works/goodthink/"/>
		<updated>2017-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://kenokeno.bingo/works/goodthink/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kenokeno.bingo/img/goodthink.gif&quot; alt=&quot;GOODTHINK&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hate. There is a lot of hate on the internet. Of course. Especially when it comes to political discussions. Those discussions ought to be more open and democratic. One approach to change this is using fake accounts—in order to be nice to people. ♥︎&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Memes ⇒ Genes ⇒ Dreams</title>
		<link href="https://kenokeno.bingo/works/memes-genes-dreams/"/>
		<updated>2018-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://kenokeno.bingo/works/memes-genes-dreams/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;padding:62.5% 0 0 0;position:relative;margin-bottom:2em;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/292558210?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Memes ⇒ Genes ⇒ Dreams = meme + Memepool + text
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memepool is the petri dish of internet culture. Uploading internet memes to the Memepool means detecting their structure. By utilising the &lt;code&gt;meme&lt;/code&gt; package manager, it is possible to sync a collection to one’s personal computer. Thus, one becomes a meme scientist.
Memepool is the &lt;em&gt;dynamic archive&lt;/em&gt; of memes. According to media theorist Wolfgang Ernst, a dynamic archive is the archetype for reconstructing reality algorithmically.
Although these postmodern times seem to be dialectical, ideologies gain a lot of power, especially those promoting a hyper-rational worldview. Cybernetics is one of them, calling itself scientific since its birth in the 20th century. Its main message: The material world works in exactly the same way as electric circuits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kenokeno.bingo/img/memesgenesdreams_01.png&quot; alt=&quot;meme: Dawkins&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One just has to know every parameter of this circuit in order to calculate the outcome. Of course, those calculations are reciprocal. Knowing the desired output, one is able to manipulate the input adequately to meet their goal.
Even though a lot of people do not know about it explicitly, cybernetics had a lot of impact on society. People use computer metaphors for describing their thinking and human metaphors for describing the functionality of computers.
The cybernetic view has influenced many techno-utopias and internet utopias: Philosophers like Rainer E. Zimmermann consider cyber-utopias as a way of creating Blochian &lt;em&gt;concrete utopias&lt;/em&gt; by proposing and testing a new social concept online. The alt-right community tries to build its own utopia. It uses internet memes to establish power. Internet memes are the new &lt;em&gt;Volksempfänger&lt;/em&gt;. As Walter Benjamin puts it: “‘Fiat ars—pereat mundus’, says Fascism, and, as Marinetti admits, expects war to supply the artistic gratification of a sense perception that has been changed by technology. This is evidently the consummation of ‘l’art pour l’art.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kenokeno.bingo/img/memesgenesdreams_02.png&quot; alt=&quot;memepool.network: Squidward&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right-wing movement shows us the manipulative use of technocratic systems by saying: “Internet memes &lt;em&gt;(culture)&lt;/em&gt; behave life genes &lt;em&gt;(technology)&lt;/em&gt; and constitute therefore the material for people’s dreams &lt;em&gt;(ideology)&lt;/em&gt;.” It is a self-perpetuating vicious cycle, a feedback loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Keynote&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/h4lxjU9YmzE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technical Appendix&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;front-end: &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/&quot;&gt;React&lt;/a&gt; (Javascript), CSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API: Django (Python)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;back-end: GitLab (Ruby, Javascript)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;package manager: C, based on pacman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kenokenobingo/meme-genes-dreams&quot;&gt;Repository: Memes ⇒ Genes ⇒ Dreams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kenokenobingo/meme&quot;&gt;Repository: meme Package Manager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kenokenobingo/memepool&quot;&gt;Repository: Memepool Front-End&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kenokenobingo/memewell&quot;&gt;Repository: Memepool Back-End&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>bauhaus. sprachrohr der studierenden</title>
		<link href="https://kenokeno.bingo/works/bauhaus-sprachrohr/"/>
		<updated>2019-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://kenokeno.bingo/works/bauhaus-sprachrohr/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kenokeno.bingo/img/bauhaus_01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bauhaus. sprachrohr der studierenden.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;bauhaus&lt;/em&gt; was a student newspaper published by &lt;em&gt;kostufra&lt;/em&gt; (Kommunistische Studentenfraktion) at Bauhaus Dessau. The issues of &lt;em&gt;bauhaus&lt;/em&gt; show various political conflicts at Bauhaus, which are highly relevant today, as well. Issue #4 was reproduced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kenokeno.bingo/img/bauhaus_02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bauhaus: Wohin geht der Weg?&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Critical Bauhaus</title>
		<link href="https://kenokeno.bingo/works/critical-bauhaus/"/>
		<updated>2019-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://kenokeno.bingo/works/critical-bauhaus/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kenokeno.bingo/img/criticalbauhaus_01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Critical Bauhaus&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bauhaus seems to be shiny and perfect during its 100th birthday. But is it? What does Bauhaus mean nowadays? And how &lt;em&gt;Bauhaus-y&lt;/em&gt; is the so called Bauhaus University in Weimar?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kenokeno.bingo/img/criticalbauhaus_02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Critical Bauhaus on the Door&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kenokeno.bingo/img/criticalbauhaus_03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Critical Bauhaus served with Parsley&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kenokeno.bingo/img/criticalbauhaus_04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Critical Bauhaus Poster for Tag der Leere on bauhaus.fm&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>ideologies.kitchen</title>
		<link href="https://kenokeno.bingo/works/ideologies-kitchen/"/>
		<updated>2019-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://kenokeno.bingo/works/ideologies-kitchen/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ideolgies are fragmenting. Those fragments are published on the internet by their followers, using platforms embedded in their ideolgies: Most of the internet’s infrastructure is based on capitalist and libertarian thinking.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;ideologies.kitchen&lt;/em&gt; produces merch for all of those fragmented ideologies, being in that sense agnostic. The actual goals of &lt;em&gt;ideologies.kitchen&lt;/em&gt; are obviously of capitalist and libertarian nature: selling goods and providing an archive of the ideologies collected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kenokeno.bingo/img/ideologies_01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kenokeno.bingo/img/ideologies_02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://kenokeno.bingo/img/ideologies_03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
